Edgar Pino

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

Edgar Pino

2571 Remington Ct, Green Bay, WI 54302

Phone: (920) 328 - 7541 Email: me@edgarpino.com Website: edgarpino.com Blog: edgardev.com

Github: https://github.com/edgar971

_

Skills

About Me:

I'm a passionate machine learning engineer with experience building scalable recommender systems, data intensive applications, and distributed systems. I have a B.S. in Computer Science and a M.S in Data Science with a capstone in Machine Learning.

Soft Skills:

Critical thinker, team leader, exceptional problem solver, great communication skills, adaptable to various environments, and positive attitude.

Languages:

Typescript, Python, Elixir, C#, and SQL.

Databases:

Postgres, Kafka, Redis, Snowflake, and Athena.

Frameworks/Tools:

Tensorflow, Pytorch, Airflow, KSQL, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, and RabbitMQ,

Experience

Pluralsight

Remote/Lehi, Utah

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

March 2020 - Current

Currently leads the ML team working on providing a personalized home page and other experiences to learners. This involves researching and implementing new recommendation models, maintaining an API to serve content recommendations, and building the infrastructure to easily iterate, experiment (multi-armed bandits), and deliver value faster.

Achievement Highlights:

- Experiment on a new type of personalized home page with dynamic carousels.
- Create a multi-armed bandit to test different models in production based on user context/features.
- Create a scalable and reliable infrastructure serving 15-20k RPM.
- Implement efficient ETL pipelines for large datasets using streaming and batch processing frameworks using KSQL and Airflow.

Software Engineer

October 2017 - March 2020

Led the team that architected and built a reliable notification system that's used by internal product teams used to communicate with end users. Started researching the next phase of the notification system around personalization using machine learning. I also helped improve the user and author profile in order to provide meaningful and useful metrics efficiently and accurately.

Achievement Highlights:

- Research ways to personalized notifications using machine learning.
- Use NLP models in combination with rule based systems to rank user notifications.
- Improved user retention with notification system.
- Reduce downtime and overall errors in notification systems.
- Created experimentation framework for A/B testing notifications.
- Architect elastic microservices to scale on demand.
- Implement efficient ETL pipelines for large datasets using streaming and batch processing frameworks.

Envano Inc.

Green Bay, Wisconsin

Software Engineer

July 2016 - October 2017

Design, implement and maintain high-traffic web frontends and

distributed backends. Develop RESTFul APIs and integrate with many Third Party integrations. Responsible for maintaining multiple cloud servers hosted with Rackspace and AWS.

Achievement Highlights:

- Successfully implemented source control into our workflow and installed Gitlab which led to improving the development team's organization, flexibility, and productivity.
- Implemented Docker for development and production environments for reliable distributed systems.
- Architect and implemented backup process for servers and laptops.
- Lead the development of various RESTFul APIs along with Third Party API integrations.
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment pipelines into our workflow process.
- Architect and developed a headless CMS and RESTFul API for a major grocery store.
- Implemented caching mechanism using NGINX and Varnish in order to improve response time and uptime.
- Created SLA and disaster recovery plan for high-level clients.

Front-End Developer

January 2014 - July 2016

Created high-quality responsive websites based on client needs. Experimented with new technologies and trends in web development in order to provide the best user experience.

Achievement Highlights:

- Developed various landing pages for new product launches for major manufacturing and equipment companies.
- Replaced many legacy front-ends written in jQuery with React.js and Angular.js.
- Introduced SASS and preprocessors to the development team which led to increased productivity and improved workflow.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign / M.S Computer Science in Data Science - Capstone in Machine Learning. June 2017 - May 2020

Lakeland University / B.S Computer Science

June 2014 - May 2016